Software Engineer

 Mobile:
 +64 020-4000-3464

 Email:
 pfellow@outlook.co.nz

LinkedIn: Link
GitHub: Link

Portfolio: pfellow.me

Career Objective

Fullstack Software Engineer role (JavaScript, TypeScript, Node.js, Next.js, React.js, Vue.js, AWS).

Skills Summary

Web Development.

Skilled in JavaScript, React.js, Vue.js, Node.js, Next.js and database and cloud (AWS) technologies, with professional experience in creating responsive web applications.

Business Analysis and Documentation.

Skilled in analysing business requirements (I took part in several IT projects as a business analyst), gathering stakeholder needs, and translating them into comprehensive project documentation.

Software Testing.

Experienced in implementing testing strategies, creating test scenarios and test cases, executing manual functional and regression tests, locating bugs, and creating bug reports to ensure the quality and reliability of software. Familiar with various TMSs and tools for test automation, such as Jest, Vitest, Cypress, and Cucumber.

AWS

I am an AWS Certified Developer - Associate (certified by AWS in October 2023).

I have skills, hands-on and professional experience in AWS Cloud Computing and ICT Infrastructure. I also use AWS for publishing my pet projects and exploring features that AWS provides.

Teamwork

Adept at collaborating with cross-functional teams, including developers, designers, and stakeholders, to achieve project objectives. Possess strong interpersonal and communication skills. I have several successful IT projects launched.

Self-development.

Committed to continuous learning and professional growth, consistently staying updated with the latest industry trends and best practices. Proactive in searching for new opportunities to enhance skills and expand my knowledge.

Experience Summary

Software Engineer - Immersve

IT Project Coordinator - Velvetech

Technical Project Coordinator - Avtomatika-Servis

Business Analyst - Delovye Linii

Senior Logistics Specialist, Logistics Specialist - Delovye Linii, DL-Trans

October 2023 - Present

July 2021 - February 2023

December 2020 - July 2021

April 2016 - December 2020

September 2010 - April 2016

Education

Qualifications

Economic Manager Economics and Construction Company Management

Vologda State Technical University, Russia 2008

Master of IT Whitireia New Zealand (Te Pūkenga) 2023

Professional Development

Advanced training: Project management and enterprise business processes

St. Petersburg State University of Economics 2016

Postgraduate course: Intelligent Systems (Machine Learning)

Peter the Great St. Petersburg Polytechnic University 2022

Technical Skills

Cloud Computing (AWS)

* Knowledgeable in cloud computing concepts and experienced in working with Amazon Web Services (EC2, S3, RDS, DynamoDB, etc) for scalable and reliable cloud infrastructure.

JavaScript, TypeScript

* Skilled in JavaScript and TypeScript programming for creating interactive and dynamic web applications (frontend and backend).

HTML, CSS, UI libraries

- * Proficient in creating structured and visually appealing web pages using HTML and CSS, ensuring a seamless user experience and responsive design across different devices.
- * Experienced in utilising CSS (such as SASS and LESS) preprocessors and libraries (such as Tailwind, Bootstrap, Material UI, and Radix UI) to enhance the styling and layout of web applications.

React.js, Vue.js

* Experienced in building modern and scalable user interfaces using React.js. Vue.js and writing unit, component and E2E tests with Jest, Vitest, Cypress and Cucumber.

Node.js + Express.js, Next.js

* Capable of building server-side applications, creating RESTful and GraphQL APIs, and handling server-side logic with Node.js, Express.js, or Next.js

SQL, NoSQL Databases

* Skilled in working with SQL databases (mostly, MySQL) and NoSQL databases (mostly, MongoDB and DynamoDB) to design, query, and manage relational databases.

Other languages I have experience in: PHP, Python, C#

Other skills: Project Management: Jira, Confluence, MS Project, Gantt Charts

Business analysis: BPMN, User Stories, Use case Modelling SWOT and PESTLE Techniques, MS Visio Software testing: Jest, Mocha+Chai+Sinon, Selenium, Testrail, Test suits/cases, Bug reporting, Unity

Detailed Experience

Software Engineer - Immersve

October 2023 - Present

- * Designing, building, and maintaining web applications using JavaScript, TypeScript, and modern frontend frameworks.
- * Creating server-side components and APIs, and managing data storage.
- * Integrating third-party APIs and deploying applications on cloud platforms using CI/CD pipelines.
- * Writing unit, component and E2E tests for code quality assurance, debugging issues, and optimizing performance across the stack.

IT Project Coordinator - Velvetech

July 2021 - February 2023

- * Participation in various IT projects as a project coordinator, business analyst, and software tester (the role depends on the project) at all stages of the project life cycle.
- * Development of a website (using Wix.com) for a legal company.
- * Coordination and organising of three teams of developers.
- * Interaction and meetings with clients and product owners, organising effective communication between team members.
- * Definition of the scope of projects and assessment of their costs.
- * Controlling changes, risks, and open issues in projects.
- * Preparation of regular project reports.

Technical Project Coordinator - Avtomatika-Servis

December 2020 - July 2021

- * Technical project coordination of two complex software development projects (with a development team of more than 30 people).
- * Formalisation of business processes and functional requirements, including the evaluation of their costs.
- * Preparation and updating of project documentation.
- * Organisation of effective communications between stakeholders, analysts, developers, and other departments.

Business Analyst - Delovye Linii

April 2016 - December 2020

* Business analysis for developing corporate information systems for operational, financial, and managerial accounting of transport and logistics companies (100 or more users) with integration with other information systems.

- * Engineering and reengineering transport and logistics business processes.
- * Organisation of business support (documentary and contractual support, reporting, interaction with suppliers, and IT companies).
- * Implementation of electronic document management.
- * Participation in IT projects (both Waterfall and Agile) as a business analyst, project coordinator, and product owner.
- * Participation in the development and testing processes of new and existing solutions.

Senior Logistics Specialist, Logistics Specialist - Delovye Linii, DL-Trans

June 2012 - April 2016

- * Participation in projects to create a vehicle queue management system in distribution centres, the creation of LTL transportation management systems, and the production schedule.
- * Interaction with the customer service department, and trucking enterprises.
- * Routing a fleet of assigned vehicles.
- * Controlling movements and monitoring the performance of vehicles.
- * Informing drivers about assignments. Liaising with the customer service department and the transport department.

Project Experience

My current work projects

My role in the project: Fullstack Developer Contact me if you want to know more.

URL Shortener

My role in the project: Fullstack Developer

This is my personal (hobby) project – a web service for shortening URL links. I launched it in 2018 and since then thousands of people used it. In addition to several options for shortening URLs, this service provides various statistics on clicks. I am refactoring it currently by changing the development framework to Next.js and the database to MongoDB.

Personal portfolio website (https://pfellow.me)

My role in the project: Developer

React.js -based one-page responsive portfolio website, containing two 3d models, smooth animations, and modern elements.

Web application for repair technicians of one of the largest American reverse logistics companies

My role in the project: Business analyst, software tester

This project aimed to provide a module that makes automated decisions on what products (mostly, electronics) should get repaired based on data collected throughout the repair and harvesting of spare parts processes. The web interface provides the opportunity for repair technicians to mimic the real repair process and record all the related events.

Web platform for a legal and risk management company

My role in the project: Business analyst, developer (Wix)

An online platform/database where all incident, medical record, and claim-related information can be easily entered by numerous medical facilities around the USA and simultaneously and instantaneously shared and accessed by all necessary parties.

B2B Wholesale Marketplace for one of the largest American electronics resellers

My role in the project: Project Coordinator

The website empowers customers with the tools they need for a premium wholesale buying and selling experience. It is the first platform to allow mixing and matching products, making intelligent buying decisions based on sales history data, and taking advantage of volume discounts.

Personal and Interests

I am patient, attentive to details, and a good team player in agile environments, though don't mind working alone if needed. I believe all conflicts can be solved (or even prevented) through communication.

I love spending my spare time swimming and hiking. I am also into playing computer, console and board games, reading and listening to science fiction books, watching sci-fi TV shows and socialising with my friends.

I'm keen on travelling and exploring new places across the globe, and, of course, honing my web development skills.

References

Can be provided upon request.